Guide to the Jack W. Rowland Works Progress Administration (WPA) in Texas records MS 1021
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jack W. Rowland Works Progress Administration (WPA) in Texas records
1931-1946
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rowland, Jack W.
MS 1021
1 Linear Feet 1 box
Records of Jack Rowland's military service in the Works Progress Administration, including formats such as newsclippings, correspondence, 1943 WPA Final Report in Texas, war ration card and other identification and induction cards. Houstonian Jack W. Rowland served as the Regional Director of the Works Project Administration from 1939-1943.
Biographical / Historical
Houstonian Jack W. Rowland served as the Regional Director of the Works Project Administration from 1939-1943.
Content Description
Records of Jack Rowland's military service in the Works Progress Administration, including formats such as newsclippings, correspondence, 1943 WPA Final Report in Texas, war ration card and other identification and induction cards.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Elizabeth Kidd, related to Jack Rowland as his niece, by marriage.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Index Terms
Subjects
World War (1939-1945)
Document Types
clippings (information artifacts); reports; letters (correspondence)
- Series I: Jack Rowland records
  - Baylor University yearbook featuring Jack Rowland, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jack Rowland letters, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Selective Services, Notice of Classification cards, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Joack Rowland ID cards (Red Cross, Attorney General of Texas, and others), 1940-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Final Report of the Texas Works Progress Administration, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jack Rowland induction papers, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Jack Rowland, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jack Rowland war ration book no. 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)